虾狐影视论坛：www.xh127.com
BD1080P吧：www.bd1080pba.com
话说在很久以前，有个猴王孙悟空
Once upon a time long ago, there was a Monkey King - Sun Wukong.
他法力高强  神通广大
He had magnificent powers beyond belief.
因为大闹天空 惹怒了玉皇大帝
He once created a tremendous uproar in the Heavenly Palace and angered the Jade Emperor.
大胆妖猴
Insolent Monkey!
你触犯天条 还不快快伏法
You have broken my laws and shall taste my wrath.
去你的吧
Mmm, tastes pretty sweet to me.
快  快抓住他
Go get him!
哪吒在此
Here comes Nezha!
放箭
Shoot!
下去吧
Down you go!
猴王把天兵打得落花流水  大获全胜
The Monkey King had defeated the whole Heavenly Army with great victory.
但是 如来佛祖却不能容忍他蔑视天庭
Yet the Grand Buddha disliked hid defiance against the Heavens.
从此以后  那孙悟空就一直被压在五行山下
Since then, Sun Wukong has been imprisoned under the Mountain of Five Elements
至今快五百年了
for the last five hundred years.
放心吧  齐天大圣是不会死的
But don't worry, Sun Wukong - The Great Sage Equaling Heavens won't die.
他只是睡着啦
He fell asleep, that's all.
天快黑了  大家抓紧赶路吧
It's getting dark, everyone back on the road.
诶  知道啦
Alright!
好嘞
Let's go!
后面的都跟上
Follow up!
小心点儿
Mind your steps!
没事
No problem.
要小心点
Be careful.
山妖来啦
Incoming Mountain Trolls!
有山妖
There are Mountain Trolls!
快下山
Down the hill!
什么呀
What is it?
一个孩子
A child.
可怜的孩子
Poor boy.
你从哪儿来啊
Where are you from?
怪可怜的
Pitiful baby.
阿弥陀佛
Gracious Buddha.
好啊
Bravo!
好好好
Great!
孙大圣
Sun Wukong the Great Monkey King
战天王
Fights the Heavenly Kings
好好好
Great!
可是孙悟空是不会死的
But Sun Wukong won't die.
江流儿
Jiang Liuer!
怎么又是你？
It's you again?
法明  法明
Fa Ming!
管好你徒弟
Discipline your disciples!
别让我再看见你
Don't ever get in sight again!
孙悟空在此
Sun Wukong is here!
毛神报上名来
Hairy monster! Announce your name!
玉帝老儿  吃俺老孙一棒
Jade joker, take that!
师父
Sifu!
流儿  你这是在干什么？
Liuer, what are you doing?
我在
I am...
化缘
begging for alms.
阿弥陀佛
Gracious Buddha.
流儿啊
Liuer.
为师就盼着你能踏踏实实的
Sifu I only hope that you can grow up diligent.
为师可没法照顾你一辈子啊
Sifu cannot always be there for you all your life.
师父
Sifu.
我们当和尚的  难道每天就为了吃饱肚子
For us monks all we do is to eat and fill our stomachs.
那和别人有什么不同啊？
How is that different to anyone else?
当然不同了
Of course it's not the same!
这化缘呢  只是做一个高僧的开始
Begging for alms is only the beginning of becoming a great monk.
打坐  念经  参禅
Meditation, reciting sutra, and zen.
不骄不躁  悠然自得
Away from arrogance and haste, be one with nature.
你看  为师现在不就很好吗？
You see, aren't Sifu I, doing well at this?
外面到处闹山妖
Mountain Trolls are everywhere.
念经又不能吓跑他们
Reciting sutras don't scare them away.
那你想怎么的呀？
What can you do about it?
我要...
I want to...
学好拳脚  打山妖
learn kung fu and knock out the Trolls.
闭嘴
Be quiet!
江流儿  你给我听好了
Jiang Liuer, now listen carefully.
我们出家人普度众生
For us monks to save the world,
要从小事做起
we start from small deeds.
专心的打坐  参禅  化缘
Focus on meditation, zen and begging for alms.
一花一世界  一叶一菩提
World is within the petal of a flower, wisdom is within the leaves.
如是知  如是见  如是信解而已
See it, believe it, interpret it.
一切皆为虚幻
Everything is illusion.
命由己造  相由心生
Life is a self made illusion from your heart.
一念愚即班若绝
One foul thought drives out all wisdom.
别老打打杀杀的
Don't get into fights.
你现在应该
Now you must...
知道了  念经  参禅...
I know, sutras, zen...
错了
No!
是接着  化缘
It's to get on with begging for alms.
是  师父
Yes, Sifu!
山妖来啦  山妖
Mountain Trolls approaching!
放箭 放箭
Shoot!
上
Go!
流儿
Liuer!
江流儿
Jiang Liuer!
一 二 四
One, two, four...
一共四十八个
That makes forty-eight altogether.
这个太大了  不要
This one is oversized, get it out.
可是老大  还差一个女娃子
Boss, we still need one girl.
女娃来了
Here comes a girl!
女娃在这里
A girl!
流儿  你在干什么呢？
Liuer, what are you doing?
小孩子别多管...
Stay out of trouble...
师父快跑
Sifu, run!
怎么回事啊？
What happened?
快  师父  流儿
- Sifu, run! - Liuer!
哎呀  你害惨我们了
It's all your fault!
师父  这边走
Sifu, this way!
师父
Sifu!
流儿  快跑
Liuer, run!
快跑
Run!
那孩子呢？
Where is that kid?
给
Here you go.
你这个笨蛋
You fool!
流儿  你在哪儿啊？
Liuer, where are you?
流儿
Liuer!
快跑
Run!
哪里来的野猴子？
What bloody baboon is that?
愣着干什么？
What are you standing there for?
上
Go get him!
大马
Horsey!
如来老儿
Buddha, you old bastard.
俺被你困了五百年
You locked me up for five hundred years.
还不够吗？
That's not enough for you?
你别忘了
You can't do this.
俺可是齐天大圣
I am the Great Sage!
齐天大圣
Great Sage Equal of Heaven!
谁在那儿？
Who's that?
给我出来
Come on out!
快点
Now!
怎么又是你？
You again?
你真的是齐天大圣吗？
Are you really the Great Sage Equal of Heaven?
是又怎么样？
Yeah, so?
他
It's him!
他真的是齐天大圣
He really is the Great Monkey King!
别跟着我
I am not the Great Sage!
小屁孩儿
Stupid kid!
大  大圣
Great Sage!
是去那边了
Over there.
多谢土地公公
Thank you Master Groundhog!
大圣
Great Sage!
等等我
Wait for me!
大圣  你在这里干什么呀？
Great Sage, what are you doing here?
没  没什么
Nothing, nothing at all.
大圣  我刚才看见你和佛像说话
Great Sage, I had just seen you talking to the Buddha's statue.
那你一定见过...
Then you must have seen...
上来呀  小屁孩儿
Catch me now, you stupid kid!
大圣
Great Sage!
你一定见过佛祖吧
You must have met the Buddha himself!
你说  我念经的时候  佛祖能听见吗？
Tell me, can Buddha hear me whenever I recite the sutra?
听见  肯定能听见
Yes. I'm sure he can.
那老头最爱管闲事儿了
The old man loves to poke his nose in everyone's business.
大圣  你一定会很多法术吧
Great Sage, you must know magic!
我知道
I know.
齐天大圣  孙悟空
Sun Wukong - the Great Sage Equal of Heaven.
身如玄铁  火眼金睛
Cast of iron with eyes of fire.
长生不老  还有七十二变
The immortal one, who can transform seventy-two times.
一个筋斗云啊  就是十万八千里
Your Somersault Cloud takes you a hundred thousand miles.
拔一根毫毛  一吹
Pull off a strand of air and blow it.
怎么什么都没有啊
How come nothing comes about?
对了  大圣
By the way, Great Sage,
你还有一根如意金箍棒
you also have a Power Pole.
话说那金箍棒  重一万三千六百斤
That might pole weights ten thousand pounds.
大圣  你的金箍棒呢？
Where is that pole of yours, Great Sage?
戏里说你给藏在耳朵里了
All the stories say that you hid it inside your ear!
给我看看
Show me!
你这小屁孩儿
You stupid little kid!
叽叽喳喳跟了俺一路  俺老孙的脑仁儿都被你吵炸了
Chattering on and on, you're gonna make my brain explode!
能不能让我安静会儿？
Can't you just leave me alone?
好
Alright.
不许再提金箍棒的事儿
No one more question about the Power Pole!
大圣  二郎神真的有三只眼睛吗？
Great Sage, does the Three-Eyed God really have three eyes?
好厉害
That's amazing!
大圣大圣  巨灵神是不是力气很大？
Great Sage, does God Juling really have the strength of giant?
很大
Yes.
四大天王是兄弟吗？
Are the Four Heavenly Kings really brothers?
是姐妹
No, they're sisters!
那哪吒是男孩吗？
Then is Nezha a boy?
女的
She's a girl.
托塔天王有塔吗？
Does the Pagoda King have a pagoda?
没有
No!
那塔里有人吗？  哎呀，没有
- Then are there people in the pagoda? - Jeez, no!
大胆孙悟空
You ruthless Sun Wukong!
俺山神奉佛祖法旨  在此看守于你
I, the Mountain Lord am here to guard you, upon Grand Buddha's order.
你怎可擅自离开
How dare you escape!
我当是谁  小小毛神
You? You're literally as dumb as a box of rocks!
既然知道你孙大圣在此
Well now that you see I am here,
还不快快给俺让开？
why don't you just leave by yourself?
孙悟空  你法印还在
Sun Wukong, you still bear the mark of Buddha's Punishment.
现在只不过是个普通的臭猴子而已
You are only a useless Monkey!
还摆什么架子
What outdated attitude is that of yours?
俺这一拳下去  还不把你...
My fist will crush you...
妖猴休走
Halt! Damned Monkey!
符咒
That spell!
哪里跑
You are going nowhere!
别动啊
Don't move.
大圣  你看
Great Sage, you see.
五行山里的东西可不好惹啊
In the Five Elements Mountain resides strange beings.
难道说那个弼马温出来了？
Had that Guardian of the Dragon been unleashed?
大王
Your Highness.
你是说那毛脸的猴子是孙悟空？
Are you saying that this hairy-faced Monkey is Sun Wukong?
本王倒要见识见识  他还有多少手段
I shall see for myself what sort of tricks he could pull off.
大圣
Great Sage!
你也在这儿啊
You are here too!
我还以为再也找不到你了
I thought I may never find you again.
把你放在山上
I left you on the mountain.
我当时好像掉下悬崖
I remember that I was falling off a cliff.
后来有只大怪鱼想吃了我们
There was that giant fish tying to eat us.
哦  我知道了
Oh, I know!
是大圣救了我们
The Great Sage saved us!
大圣
Great Sage!
谢谢你  救了我们
Thank you for saving us!
不不不  师父说出家人不能吃肉
No thanks, Sifu said that us monks must not eat meat.
和  和尚？
Monks?
我叫江流儿  是个挂单的和尚
My name is Jiang Liuer, I am a monk.
我师父叫法明  我们住在长安城
My Sifu is Fa Ming, we come from Chang'an the Capital.
我
I...
那你们跑这五行山干什么啊？
Then what are you doing on this "mountain of doom"?
都是可恶的山妖  它们到处抓小孩子
Those horrible Trolls, they kidnap children!
我  我无意中看到她
I bumped into her.
然后  然后山妖就一直追我们
Then the beasts chased after us.
所以我们就跑到这儿来了
Then we ended up here.
可恶的山妖
Terrible Trolls!
可是  现在好了
But now everything is fine.
我们跟着大圣
Since the Great Monkey King is our protector,
就什么也不怕了
we are afraid of nothing!
我说过要保护你吗？
Who's going to protect you?
出了这山  咱们井水不犯河水
Once we get off this mountain, we'll go our separate ways, okay?
可是大圣
But...
小心  烫啊
Be careful, it's hot!
大圣？
Great Sage?
没事啊  没事
Leave me! I'm safer up here anyway.
哎~真是个傻丫头
Little One!
大圣  这里有个庙
Great Sage, there is a temple ahead.
大圣
Great Sage.
大圣  佛祖显灵了
Great Sage! Buddha had revealed his magic.
佛祖？
Buddha?
妖怪  你快放下傻丫头
Monster, leave the little girl alone!
这可是齐天大圣孙悟空
He is Sun Wukong, the Great Sage Equal of Heaven!
齐天大圣？
"Great Sage"?
你看他那一头杂毛  还齐天大圣呐
No offense, but that chimp doesn't look like he's "Great" at anything.
我还是天蓬元帅呢
I would go around calling myself the Pagoda King.
他还真把自己当孙悟空了
He really thinks he's Sun Wukong!
小孩  来帮本帅拿着
Kid, hold this for me.
看我来教训这个  齐天大圣
I'll prove to you that this Great Sage is nothing but a Great Fake.
孙猴子  看招
Monkey King, see this!
真是他
It's really him.
臭猴子
You stinking fleabag!
当年被你害的  掉下天界
You're the reason I came crashing down here in the first place, with this PIG SNOUT on my face!
五百年来天天饿肚子
Nothing to eat but pig slop for the last 500 years.
你看我都瘦成什么样了
Look at how skinny I've gotten!
本帅今天跟你玩命了
I won't let you get away with this!
好啊  想报仇  来呀
It's real handy place to hang on to.
臭猴子  你别走啊  有本事你别走啊
Same old Sun Wukong! Toss me aside and walk away!
走远了
He does that.
本帅今天饶了你  别让我再看见你
Well good riddance! You're lucky I'm so forgiving!
你是  不敢去吧
You are actually afraid to go after him, right?
胡说 这深山老林的 他跑那么快 哪找去
No, I've got a busy schedule, places to go, food to steal.
天蓬元帅好像还没有土地公公厉害
Even Master Groundhog seem way more powerful than the Pagoda King.
什么？  土地
Groundhog? Now hang on.
本帅当年统领十万天兵
I'm the Pagoda King, okay? I lead an army of a hundred thousand.
三十六变出神入化
I can transform into whatever I want!
那个臭猴子五百年没洗澡了
And with this nose, I can track the stink on that Monkey for miles.
老子问着他那一身膻味  就能找着他
He can't just walk away. Not this time!
真的？  小孩看好别眨眼
- Really? - Don't blink.
待本帅变成哮天犬  前去捉拿于他
I'll turn myself into a PANTHER and hunt down that hairball.
这是？
What is that?
真是哮天犬
It really is a panther!
走喽  捉拿大圣去者
Let's go! Capture that Monkey!
真去啊
We're really going?
大圣不是去那边了吗？
Didn't the Great Sage go that way?
大圣  大圣在那边
Great Sage! He is over on that side!
大圣
Great Sage!
大圣等一下
Wait for us, Great Sage!
大圣
Great Sage!
天蓬元帅要和你比个高低
The Pagoda King wants to challenge you!
奇怪  刚才还在呢
That's strange, he was there just then.
大圣  你们认识吗？
Great Sage, do you know each other?
他真的是天蓬元帅？
Is he really the Pagoda King?
我怎么觉得他有点像...
How comes he seems like...
一只猪
He seems like a pig.
那也比他以前好看多了
And believe me, a pig is an improvement.
可是他的三十六变很厉害
But his transformations were quite something.
那就是一口气的事儿
He can't do it for very long. Only as long as a breath.
说变回来就变回来
And then, boom. Back to a pig.
猪大叔  原来你在这儿啊
Uncle Pig! Here you are!
我还以为你不敢来了呢
I thought you are no longer coming!
既然不肯善罢甘休  出手吧
You come back here to get thrown by your nose again?
太好玩了  和我一样啊
Cool! He turned into another me!
就是肚子比我大
He has bigger bellies though.
真好玩儿  再变一次
That's magic! One more time please!
大圣  你看
Great Sage! Look!
闪开
Get out of the way!
别过来
Stay back!
别动
Don't move!
都别动
Nobody moves!
大圣
Great Sage.
它  被你吓跑了
You scared it away!
你刚才差点被吃掉，知道吗？
You could've gotten yourself killed, okay?
你惹那条白龙干什么
Why do you get in that White Dragon's way?
都是你
Not for you, hamhock!
都是你这多事的猪妖，就该拿你去喂龙
You probably led him right to us. You're the one who should be dragon meat!
来啊，不就是只龙嘛
Not the ears! My face can't take anymore!
大圣，放了他吧
Great Sage, please spare him!
都是我不好
It's all my fault.
好啊
Let's see if pigs can fly.
别别
No!
你怎么老替他说话？
Why do you always speak up for him?
他耳朵都红了
His ears are blushed!
大圣  龙飞了
Great Sage! The dragon is flying!
猴子你再不放手  我可跟你急了啊
Let go of ears, will you? I don't need this abuse,
我真跟你急了
being a pig is bad enough!
龙真的能飞
That Dragon can really fly!
自由自在的，挺美
That's pure freedom, soaring through the clouds like that.
我要是能飞就好了
It would be great if I could fly.
会飞有什么啊，我还会飞呢
I did too, you know. All over the sky, no big deal.
那样就能飞过大山，找到师父
So that I can fly over the mountains and find Sifu.
带着傻丫头回家
Bring the Little One back home.
有一天你要是够坚强，够勇敢
You might someday if you're brave enough.
你就能驾驭它们
Then you can go as far as you want.
大圣，你说的是真的吗？
Great Sage, can you tell me more?
大圣
Great Sage.
你去过龙宫，龙王是不是很大？
You have been to the Dragon's Palace. Is the Dragon King humongous?
大是大，就是小气
Yeah, but he was really stingy.
对了，大圣
Oh, Great Sage.
这世上是不是有很多龙？
Are there many dragons in this world?
嗯，有水的地方就有啊
Wherever there is water, there are dragons.
我不是一块石头
也不是一滴眼泪
我只是一只小鸟
在寻找家的方向
我不是一粒沙子
也不是一声轻叹
我只是一个孩子
在寻找爱的怀抱
这是飞一样的感觉
这是自由的感觉
在撒满星星的天空迎着风飞舞
凭着一颗永不哭泣勇敢的心
这是同样的感觉
这是颤抖的感觉
在布满力量的大地带着痛狂奔
凭着一颗永不哭泣勇敢的心
前面好像有户人家
There is an inn over there!
有吃的了
They'll have a kitchen!
小师父，等等我啊
Young Master,Wait for me!
大圣，你快点
Great Sage, hurry up!
待着，别动
Stay and don't move!
欢迎光...
Welcome...
打扰了，有人在吗？
Excuse us! Anybody home?
有人在吗？
Anyone home?
怎么没人啊
No one is here.
人在
Coming...
有人吗？
Someone here?
大叔，我们路过这儿
Good Sir, we are traveling by your inn,
想在这儿借宿一宿
and wish to spend the night here.
啊？借什么？
Spend what?
怠慢了，怠慢了啊
Please excuse our shabby service.
别介意啊
Don't mind him.
他呀，脑袋缺根弦儿
He is just a bit stupid.
小师傅，你这是要去哪儿啊？
Young Master, where are you heading?
我们要去长安城
We are going to Chang'an the Capital.
好可爱的孩子啊
What a cutie little girl!
还不快去倒茶
Hurry up and bring tea!
长安城啊
Chang'an, the Capital!
小师傅，这长安城可去不得呀
Young Master, Chang'an is not your brightest spot to go.
听说那儿正在闹妖
We heard that Trolls are all over town there.
妖怪  妖怪啊
Trolls! Monster! Trolls!
妖怪
Trolls!
妖怪  妖怪啊
Trolls! Monster! Trolls!
施主，别怕别怕
Don't be afraid!
他们是好人
They are good people.
这是好人？
They are kind?
他们只是长得奇怪
They only look rather strange, that's all.
小师父说你长得很奇怪
"Strangely handsome", am I right?
您放心
Don't worry.
我们只是想在贵店借宿一宿，明天一早就走
We just want to spend the night here and hit the road in the morning.
真  真的吗？-真的
- Really? - Really!
那  那跟我来吧
Alright, follow me then.
谢谢施主
Thank you, Ma'am.
不碍事，不碍事
No worries, no worries.
毛猴子，你怎么毛利毛糙的
Hey, you're making me look stupid!
几位驾到，咱这小店真是蓬荜生辉啊
You kind visit makes my humble inn grateful.
床
Bed over here.
各位休息啊，有什么需要请尽管吩咐
Have a good rest. Let me know if there is anything you would need.
还傻站着干嘛？干活儿去
Why are you standing there? Get to work!
这孩子怎么哭得没完没了的？
What's with all the crying?
傻丫头，别哭了  睡觉了，好不好？
Little One, don't cry. Let's get some sleep, shall we?
你看，我这还有一个齐天大圣哦
Look, I still have a Great Sage here!
送给你好不好
I'll give it to you.
有了他保护你
With him as your protector,
就什么也不用怕了
you won't be afraid of anything.
快睡吧
Bedtime.
真是个废物
Useless!
这儿真安静
It's quiet here.
听惯了丛林里的声音
We've grown to be so close to the sounds of the forest.
现在都有点睡不着了
I can't get any sleep now.
你这才几天啊
Better for me,
我才睡不着呢
you snore anyway.
也是啊
True.
大圣，我要是找到师父了
Great Sage, if I ever do find my Sifu
傻丫头也回家了，你去哪儿啊？
and bring the Little One home, where will you go?
花果山
Huaguo Shan - Mountain of Flowers and Fruits.
Mountain of Flowers and Fruits.
我知道，戏文里说过
I know that one from the stories.
戏文里说花果山福地洞天
Stories say that the Mountain is a joyous place.
漫山遍野都是果树花草
Full of trees, fruits and flowers.
山水环绕，四季如春
Surrounded by beautiful nature.
对了，戏文里说那的桃子有碗那么大呢
Stories say that peaches there are huge like a bowl!
戏里的东西你也信
You believe every story you hear?
其实，有脸盆那么大呢
Actually, the peaches are big as a basin.
有脸盆那么大
As basin!
那花果山离这里有多远呢?
How far away are we from your Mountain?
差着十万八千里呢
A hundred thousand miles!
我得走一辈子
I'd have to walk all my life to get there.
不过，这对大圣来说也不算什么
But that would not be the case for the Great Monkey King.
那是，俺老孙这一个跟头就是十...
No sweat! I could make that with one leap through the clouds...
大圣
Great Sage.
等我把傻丫头送回家，我一定好好念经
When I sent the Little One home, I will work hard on reading the sutras.
因为大圣说佛祖会听见
Because you said that Buddha himself can hear me.
那样，我就可以求佛祖把大圣的法力变回来了
So that I can pray to Buddha to give your magic powers back to you.
你这小屁孩啊，整天唠叨
You little brat, mumbling nonsense all day long.
如来老儿，都被你唠叨烦了，这万一一发怒再给我罪加一等，那
Don't bother Buddha with my problems. He might just lock me up again.
也许吧
Maybe he should.
你在这里干什么？
What are you doing there?
怎么那么紧张啊？
Why are you so tense?
又偷吃东西呢，是不是
You must be stealing food again!
楼上有什么动静吗？
What's happening upstairs?
诶，我说
Hey.
你还傻站在那儿干什么啊？
What are you still standing there?
过来
Over here!
你说
Tell me,
我就奇了怪了
because I find it strange,
这猴子能有多大能耐啊
how could that Monkey be so dangerous?
还让我们费那么大的劲儿
Why are we made to be so careful of him?
咱们大王也忒小心了吧
Our Lord is too cautious about him.
跟你说话呢
I'm talking to you.
要我说啊
If I were the Lord,
咱们就直接冲上去，把他拿下
I would just tie him up straight away!
你干嘛呀？
What are you doing?
等等
Wait!
我就是随便说说
I'm just saying if!
哎呦，你这蠢货
You fool!
要是坏了大王的好事，你不想活啦
If you ruin our Lord's plan, it's game over for you!
再等等
Wait, hold!
你这蠢猪，竟敢耍我
You damn pig, how dare you fool me!
救命啊
Help!
小小伎俩还想骗你孙爷爷
I had a feeling the service here would be terrible... but wow.
小心
Take cover!
小师傅，你去哪儿啊?
Young Master, where are you going?
救孩子
Go save the kids!
你怎么咬屁股啊
Get your hands off my bacon!
快跑
Get out of here!
走
Go!
走啊
Let's go!
那猴子呢？
Where is that Monkey?
大圣，这边
Great Sage! Over here!
上船
Get on the boat!
快啊
Come on!
抱一下
Hold her!
大圣
Great Sage!
大圣，你看
Great Sage, you see.
快，快放下她
Leave her alone!
什么齐天大圣嘛
The Great Sage, Equal of what?
不过是只没有用的猴子
Nothing but a useless Monkey.
小师傅，出家人不得无礼
Young Master, monks are not allowed to be rude.
孙悟空，你也有今天
Sun Wukong, here you are again.
大圣
Great Sage!
我们快去救傻丫头吧！大圣
Please go and rescue the Little One! Great Sage!
我管不了
She's not my problem.
大圣，大圣
Great Sage.
我都说了，我管不了
Neither are you!
我管不了那孩子
She's yours, you can take care of her yourself.
猴子，你消消气儿
He can't. You know that.
别叫我猴子
You want to be the hero? Go ahead!
你给我闭嘴，你这个蠢猪
I didn't ask to be saddled with any of you!
可是...可是现在只有你能救她...
But... you are the protector! The legends say...
我去救她
I will go to rescue her.
小师父，小师父
Liuer! It's too dangerous for you!
猴子，小师父跑了
Sun, you can't leave these kids, not now.
猴子
Monkey!
该死的猴子
Damned Monkey!
哎呦...疼死我啦
Ouch... that hurts!
快走，大王的祭祀要赶不上了
Hurry, or we won't make it to the Lord's ceremony!
大圣，我们快去救傻丫头吧！大圣
Great Sage, Please go and rescue the Little One! Great Sage...
这...
I...
我管不了
I don't want this!
管不了，管不了
These people are nothing but trouble!
大圣
Great Sage.
你看我这还有一个齐天大圣哦
Look, I still have the a Great Sage here!
送给你好不好
You can have it.
有了它保护你，就什么也不用怕了
With him as your protector, you won't be afraid of anything.
猴子
Monkey!
你还活着吗？你
Are you still alive?
你倒是说句话啊
Say something!
我知道你心里不痛快
I know I'm a big pain in the neck.
可你...
But...
别忘了，你可是齐天大圣啊
You want to be king again? Be the "Great Sage" that kid thinks you are!
齐天大圣 - 孙悟空
Sun Wukong - The Great Monkey King.
身如玄铁，火眼金睛
Cast of iron with eyes of fire.
长生不老，还有七十二变
He is the immortal one, who can do seventy-two transformations.
一个筋斗云啊，就是十万八千里
A single somersault takes him a hundred thousand miles.
老猪
Pig!
跟我走
Follow me!
五行山，有寺宇兮
Ancient temples stood, upon the Mountain of Five Elements
于江畔，而飞檐
By the long river, under magnificent eaves
借童男童女之精华兮
I take the essence of children
求仙药，而历险
For alchemy to mark my quest for eternal longevity
点点羊羊
Eeeny, meeny, miney, mo...
点到谁来当肥羊
Put the baby on the Po.
小师傅，咱真有缘呢
Young Master, here we are again.
长能耐了
You have grown to be quite a warrior.
来来来，这边儿
Come over here.
流儿，你没事吧?
Liuer, are you alright?
师父，你怎么来了？
Sifu, why are you here?
师父千辛万苦才找到你
I have finally found you!
带你出去，你可千万别再乱跑了
I will get you out of here, please don't get in trouble again.
我一定好好打坐，参禅，化缘
I promise I will meditate and zen and beg everyday.
出家人欺瞒佛祖，会遭报应的
It's a sin for a monk to lie to Buddha.
这就是报应
That is the punishment.
师父，你看
Sifu, look!
这么多孩子啊
There are so many kids!
怎么还傻站着
What are you standing there for?
师父
Sifu!
傻丫头
Little One!
大王，快来不及了
My Lord, the time is running out!
孙悟空，你三番五次坏我好事
Sun Wukong, you had ruined my day too many times.
流儿
Liuer.
孙悟空那个懦夫呢？
Tell me! Where is that wimp?
他不是懦夫
He is no wimp!
你快说
Speak at once!
在哪儿？
Where is he?
大圣，是大圣来了
Great Sage! He is here!
真有齐天大圣啊
The Great Sage Equal of Heavens is for real?
该死的臭猴子
Damn Monkey!
妖怪
Listen up!
俺老孙在此，还不快快...
I'm the Monkey King. And I'm here for...
天蓬元帅在此
So am I! The Pagoda King!
妖怪，你摊上大事儿了
Monsters! You are all in big trouble!
老猪，小心
Be careful! Piggy!
不堪一击
Useless.
不要靠近他们
Leave the children alone!
大圣
Great Sage!
孙悟空
Sun Wukong,
这味道比蟠桃如何呀？
how's this taste compared to your peach of immortality?
我说了
I said...
不要...靠近他们
leave... them... alone!
大圣
Great Sage.
放手
Let go!
大圣
Great Sage!
我没事儿
I'm fine.
歇会儿，一起走啊
Just let me have a rest, then we can leave together.
接着，别再弄丢了
Hey, I think you lost this.
快走
Run!
快跑
师父，我去帮大圣
Sifu, I'm going to help Great Sage!
流儿
Liuer!
小心啊
Be careful!
是
Yes, Sifu!
大圣，我能帮你做什么？
Great Sage, what can I do for you?
谁让你回来的？你来干什么？
What are you doing? Why are you back here?
快走啊，走
Get out of here! Go!
可是你说好了，要一起走的
But you promised that we would leave together.
傻瓜，你忘了，我是齐天大圣
Have you forgotten that I am the Great Sage Equal of Heaven.
我是不会死的
I never die.
大圣
Great Sage.
江流儿，你要干什么？
Don't be stupid, Liuer!
江流儿！- 吃我一棍
- Jiang Liuer! - Take it!
住手
No!
你这个大肉虫子
You big worm!
我在这儿呀，你来啊
I am here, come on!
江流儿
Liuer!
傻瓜，傻瓜
You stupid kid!
江流儿
Liuer!
大圣
Great Sage!
江流儿...
Liuer...
江流儿
Liuer!
大圣
Great Sage.
Great Sage!
从前的我 - 陈洁仪
心里的呼唤 总在徘徊
风中的云彩 它向我走来
远处那个人 还在等待
熟悉的声音 已不在
你说你要离开
明天还会回来
曾经忘不掉的
如今你是否还记得来
转身不算告别
分离却分不开
若是遇见从前的我
请带他回来
你说你要离开
曾经忘不掉的
如今你是否还记得来
转身不算告别
分离却分不开
若是遇见从前的我
请带他回来